# MEHMET KÜLAHCI DEVOPS ENGINEER

E-mail: mhmtklhci@gmail.com Phone Number: 5074987791

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mehmet-külahcı">https://www.linkedin.com/in/mehmet-külahcı</a>
Address: Kayseri, Türkiye

**GitHub**: <a href="https://github.com/MehmetKulahci">https://github.com/MehmetKulahci</a>

## **SUMMARY**

4+ years of experience in IT including 1+ in ERP, 2+ System Network and 1+ years in **DevOps** and **Project Management**. Passionate about automation of IT processes. Designing and building effective **Continuous Integration and Delivery (CI/CD) pipelines** using **containerization**, **orchestration**, **monitoring**, infrastructure automation tools, configuration management tools, and **AWS** solutions. Able to use **Jira** as a project management tool and Agile methodology as a project management method. Highly adaptable, flexible professional who embraces teamwork but also likes to work independently. Armed with remarkable problem solving, multitasking, and time management abilities.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Pronic Yazılım Sep 2022 – Present

## **Product Support Specialist**

- Installation of Windows Server 2016-2019.
- Installation and configuration of MSSQL Server.
- Financial reporting with SQL (view, function, trigger, and stored procedure)
- Creating customer workflow with e-flow
- Installation, configuration, and ERP consulting for Tiger Enterprise.
- IT support services
- IT system troubleshooting.

(Note: Worked on widows containers to determine how two ERP applications run on server-2016)

Clarusway LLC June 2022 – Present

**AWS & DevOps Engineer Trainee** 

- Hands-on experience in AWS provisioning and solid knowledge of AWS services like EC2, S3, ELB,
   RDS, IAM, Route 53, VPC, Autoscaling, CloudFront, Cloud Watch, Cloud Formation, Security Groups,
   EKS, ECR, and coding applications with Python.
- Built and Managed AWS infrastructure As A Code with Cloud Formation.
- Worked on Containerization and Virtualization Projects with Docker and Kubernetes.
- Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using Jenkins and Git.
- Write **Ansible** playbooks and modules to deploy, configure, and manage servers.
- Automated the build & deployments for many applications from end-to-end using CI/CD strategies with various DevOps tools and technologies.
- Monitor, analyze, and report performance statistics for cloud-hosted environments by using AWS
   Cloud Watch, Prometheus, Grafana.
- Built and configured 200+ EC2 instances on AWS cloud platform, the configuration of elastic load balancer (ELB) for traffic control for the EC2 instances and S3.
- Used **Maven** as build tools on Java projects for the development of build artifacts on the source code.

# Çemrek Bilgi Teknolojileri

May 2020 - Sep 2021

#### **System And Network Specialist**

- Install and manage firewalls (Pfsense, bgnet, Fortigate) SSL VPN configuration.
- Installation and management of Veeam Backup and Replication.
- Installation and administration of virtualization software. (VirtualBox, Hyper-V, VMware ESX)
- Lenovo, HPE, and Dell server installation and configuration.
- Installation of 10+ Windows Server 2016-2019.
- Provision for network topology creation and improvement.
- Unifi and Tp-link wireless network configuration
- Installation and management of IP cameras, analog cameras, NVRs, and DVRs.
- IT support services

## Tekno-Erciyes Bilişim

Apr 2019 - Mar 2020

#### System And Network Specialist (Owner)

- Installing and managing more than 10+ firewall (Pfsense, bqnet, Fortigate)
- Configuration of an SSL VPN.
- Installation and administration of virtualization software. (VirtualBox, Hyper-V, VMware ESX)
- Lenovo, HPE, and Dell server installation and configuration.

- Installation of Windows Server 2016-2019.
- Provision for network topology creation and improvement.
- Configuring a wireless network with Unifi and Tp-link
- Installation and management of IP cameras, analog cameras, NVRs, and DVRs.
- IT support service

# **PROJECTS**

- Web Page Application (Postgresql-Nodejs-React) deployed on EC2's with Ansible, Docker, and Nginx Proxy Server.
- Microservice Architecture for Web Application with MySQL using Kubernetes.
- Jenkins Pipeline for Dockerized Application Deployed on **Docker Swarm**.
- Dockerization of Web API with MySql.
- An application deployed on AWS Application Load Balancer with Auto Scaling and RDS using Terraform.
- Create Apache Servers with Terraform.
- An Application (Django) deployed on AWS Application Load Balancer with Auto Scaling, S3, RDS, VPC's Components, Lambda, DynamoDB, and Cloudfront with Route53.
- Static Website deployed on **AWS Cloudfront**, S3, and Route53 using Cloudformation.

## **AWS Hands-On Experience on:**

• EC2, CloudFormation, ECR, DynamoDB, CloudFront, S3, API GW, Lambda, EFS, Boto3, CloudWatch, RDS, MariaDB, ALB with ASG, Apache, Nginx, Snapshots, Volumes, VPC, WordPress, Route53, Certificate Manager, IAM, AMI.

#### **DevOps Hands-On Experience on:**

- **Docker:** Installing basic operations, handling volumes, networking, image basic operations, composing operations, dockerize to-do app on python-flask, swarm basic operations, swarm network managing services, secrets, tasks.
- **Kubernetes:** Installing and basic operations, networking service discovery, Microservice deployment, and auto-scaling, managing secrets and config maps, pods and volumes, managing Kubernetes cluster with EKS, dynamic volume provisioning, and ingress.
- **Ansible:** Using modules with ad-hoc commands, using playbooks with tasks, using secrets, provisioning a web and DB server with dynamic websites, working with dynamic inventory, using roles.
- **Jenkins:** Installing, building Jenkins job, building Jenkins pipeline, installing and configuring tomcat, deployment to the staging environment, building pipeline with docker ECR.
- Terraform: Installing Terraform and building AWS infrastructure with Terraform.
- Nexus: Installing and using Proxy Repository on EC2 Instance.
- Kadıoğlu Manufacturing Facility:

Manufacturing facility server configuration, networking and Hyper-V configuration, WLAN configuration with unifi

• ASPDOOR Engineering:

Setup and configuration of Lenovo servers with VMware, creating factory LAN, configuring Fortigate and configuring IP CCTV, NVR.

• Kırşehir Concorate Test Lab:

Setup and configuration of HPE server with VMware and configuring LAN with pfsense firewall.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python | SQL | HTML | CSS | Linux | Git | GitHub | Cloud(AWS) | CloudFormation | EC2 | ECR | DynamoDB | CloudFront | S3 | API GW | Lambda | EFS | Boto3 | CloudWatch | RDS | MariaDB | ALB with ASG | Apache | Nginx | Snapshots | Volumes | VPC | Route53 | Certificate Manager | IAM | AMI | Jenkins | Docker | Kubernetes | Jira | Slack | Ansible | Terraform | Scrum/Kanban | VMWARE

# **SOFT SKILLS**

Motivation | Initiative | Leadership | Teamwork | Flexibility | Critical Thinking | Problem Solving |

## **EDUCATION**

• Clarusway LLC Virginia/USA (Remote)

June 2022 - Present

AWS & DevOps Engineering

Erciyes University

Sept 2014 - July 2018

Electrical-Electronic Engineering

Anatolia University

Sept 2014 - July 2018

**Bachelor of Business Management** 

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Clarusway AWS/DevOps Course Certification
- Zero to Hero Docker Ozgur ÖZTÜRK-UDEMY
- Her Yönüyle SQL Server
- Uygulamalarla SQL Server

# **LANGUAGES:**

Turkish : Native

English : B1